

LEAD/ SR **WEB DEVELOPER** 

#### Contact Info



**Q** 0433 681 143



Geelong, Victoria



🖂 santhudadiegmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/sa nthoshdadi

#### Portfolio

Below are some of the recent projects i worked and lead the projects and all these projects are custom Wordpress builds.

- safetransport.vic.gov.au
- svi.edu.au
- nrlquality.org.au

- atic.svi.edu.au
- christiancollege.vic.edu.au

#### Employment Preference

Remote or Hybrid

References

Available upon request

### **SUNNY DADI**

As an experienced Sr Web Developer with over 8 years of experience, I have worked with various CMS platforms mainly Wordpress, Joomla, Shopify, Weebly, and Squarespace in different industries. My reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements is excellent. I have consistently saved costs while increasing profits for my clients.

Currently, I am managing 150 sites in various industries like Government, Public Health, research, education, disability, ecommerce, and leading a team of 3 developers. My expertise also includes working knowledge of digital marketing campaigns like Google ads, shopping ads, and youtube ads and SEO best practices and also team management with day to day development tasks and workflows.

#### SKILLS

- Front End Web Development
- Custom Theme Development
- Plugin Development
- Advanced Custom Fields customisation
- Gravity forms Customisation
- Tender Scoping and Quoting the website development projects.
- · Website Accessibility analysis and optimisation
- Woocommerce, Joomla, Shopify.
- Website updates / Website support and Maintenance
- Server or Hosting Setup and management (Both WHM Cpanel and non Cpanel)
- Sever and Website Security

- Website optimisation strategies
- SEO Config (Yoast and Rankmath)
- Complex DNS management
- Cloudflare setup
- Technical analysis
- · Keyword optimisation
- Data analysis
- Strong time management
- Digital marketing
- Google Adwords
- Google Merchant Centre
- Design patterns and principles
- Google Analytics
- Google Search console
- Proficient in Adobe Creative Suite
- Team management
- Site or Server Migrations

#### TECH STACK

Programming Languages: PHP, JS, jQuery, HTML, SCSS, CSS, liquid

Database: MySQL

Web Server: Apache or Nginx

IDE or Code Editor: Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text

Preprocessors: Gulp and Webpack

Version Control System: Git

Development Flow: Local - Staging - Production

#### PROJECT MANAGEMENT TOOLS

Monday, Slack, Email, Next Cloud, Google Sheets and Microsoft and Adobe creative Suite

#### EDUCATION

Cambridge International College Melbourne (2009 - 2012)
Diploma of Multimedia & Graphic Arts - Information Technology, Multimedia

Jawaharlal Nehru Tech University, Hyderabad Bachelor of Technology Electrical & Electronics Engineering

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Responsive Web Development Certification

<u>jQuery UI Development</u>

JavaScript and JQuery Essentials Certification

**Bootstrap** 

WordPress: Accessibility

WordPress: Action and Filter Hooks

WordPress: REST API
WordPress: WP-CLI

#### WORK HISTORY

## LEAD/SR WEB DEVELOPER GRINDSTONE CREATIVE - AGENCY GEELONG, VICTORIA | DEC 21 - CURRENT

- Crafting dynamic websites for government, public sector, and healthcare clients
- Keeping a portfolio of 150 websites up-to-date and running smoothly
- Leading team of 3 web developers on day to day basis making sure all the development goes smooth and help them when needed.
- Scoping and estimating costs for the new tenders and builds.
- Making sure websites have e-commerce capabilities and engaging retail sections
- Boosting website performance by optimising web assets for speed and compatibility
- Using my skills in HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, and other libraries to implement cutting-edge features on custom Wordpress themes.
- Providing reliable web hosting solutions and uploading files to hosting accounts
- Implementing effective SEO strategies for maximum online visibility and engagement
- Handling technical issues and troubleshooting requests to keep websites running seamlessly
- Maintaining website efficiency and security by regularly patching interfaces
- Conducting rigorous testing and reviews to ensure website designs are responsive and effective
- Establishing a robust web hosting presence tailored to specific requirements

## WEB DEVELOPER (WORDPRESS / SHOPIFY) ARTHUR ST DIGITAL - AGENCY GEELONG, VICTORIA | JAN 21 - NOV 21

- Designed, implemented and monitored websites and landing pages for continuous improvement using CMS Platforms Wordpress, Joomla, Shopify.
- Managed regular maintenance and updates as well as troubleshooting of 30 websites across various clients and industry websites.
- · Oversaw troubleshooting of technical and analytical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently
- Determined coding requirements for site creation, including e-commerce capability.
- Maximized user flow in retail section of website
- Optimized web assets for speed and performance, Designed sites to be compatible with leading browsers, including Firefox, Chrome and Safari
- Used programming capabilities in HTML, CSS, PHP, JS and jQuery and other libraries as needed
- Established web hosting for sites and uploaded site files to hosting account
- Built, implemented and updated effective SEO strategies
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.
- Provided ongoing efficiency and security maintenance and patching on website interface to maintain viability after launch.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Generated web hosting presence to accommodate specified needs, uploading and maintaining files on account.

# ECOMMERCE BDM / WEB DEVELOPER CARONLAB AUSTRALIA PVT LTD NORTH GEELONG, VICTORIA | FEB 2017 - JAN 21

- Built and managed 10 Ecommerce websites and 8 Static websites using Wordpress and Woocommerce.
- Oversaw troubleshooting of technical and analytical issues to solve problems quickly and efficiently
- Customised the websites to support ecommerce functionalities and requirements.
- Server set and management from Deployment to Security and sub domains etc.
- Integrated Ecommerce websites with various market places (Ebay, Amazon, My Deal, Catch)
- Implemented Google Campaigns and SEO for various types of websites
- · Established web hosting for site and uploaded site files to hosting account
- Produced and submitted regular reports outlining progress against KPI objectives
- Built, implemented and updated effective SEO strategies
- Performed in-depth competitor reviews to check competitor activities with ad placement, keyword use, placement bids and landing pages
- Oversaw technical issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

### ADCEL GROUP | RED ONION CREATIVE GEELONG, VICTORIA | APR 2015 - FEB 2017

- Developed wireframes, site maps for new website designs
- Worked with both branded and unbranded websites to develop wireframes and HTML mockups for web prototypes.
- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website
- Created eye catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms to strengthen company brand and identity
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans
- Implemented Google Campaigns and SEO for various types of websites

#### **WEB DESIGNER**

### CHANDLER MAIL MARKETING, MELBOURNE SEP 2012 - FEB 2015

- Designed and prepared technical reports, studies and related documentation
- Employed effective time management when dealing with coordination and accountability around personnel and security assets
- Collected data by identifying sources of information, including designing survey and collection methods
- Used Adobe Creative Suite to create images and layouts
- Completed final touches for projects such as images sizes and font selection
- Put together videos for social media, advertising and informational purposes
- Developed print materials such as brochures, banners and signs
- · Coordinated, created and scheduled content, designs and periodic updates to company website